<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-21T12:14:57-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/index.xml</id><title type="html">Kiara Bickers - Official Site | How to Get Started With Bitcoin</title><subtitle>Bitcoin Clarity explains what Bitcoin is, why it works, and if it can work for you.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bitcoin Wallets: Getting Started With The Basics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/17/what-is-a-bitcoin-wallet" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bitcoin Wallets: Getting Started With The Basics" /><published>2020-05-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/17/what-is-a-bitcoin-wallet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/17/what-is-a-bitcoin-wallet">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-best-bitcoin-wallet-in-2020&quot;&gt;What is the best bitcoin wallet in 2020?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/02-bitcoin-wallets/bitcoin-core-screeshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;bitcoin core screeshot&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoincore.org/en/download/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Core&lt;/a&gt; is the best wallet available. If there was an official bitcoin wallet this would be it, and it’s free. Bitcoin Core may not be the most user friendly since it’s for the more advanced “power users”, but it’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lopp.net/bitcoin-node-performance-sync-tests/&quot;&gt;highest performing&lt;/a&gt; full node you can run, and it’s the only way to use Bitcoin peer-to-peer. Bitcoin Core can also be used with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-core/HWI&quot;&gt;hardware wallet&lt;/a&gt; or privacy wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-the-best-bitcoin-wallet-for-beginners&quot;&gt;So what is the best bitcoin wallet for beginners?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trust is that there isn’t a single best wallet it is about trade-offs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the complete beginners’ guide to wallets! I’ll start with the basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-difference-between-a-bitcoin-app-and-other-payment-apps&quot;&gt;What is the difference between a bitcoin app and other payment apps?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With most major payment apps every transaction is covered by the bank’s fraud protection. Meaning that if you someone steals your funds, or if you have been a victim of fraud, you have a company waiting in the wings to bail you out. This is not the case with cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With any bitcoin wallet, you’re taking complete control of your funds. This means also that if you lose those funds there is no one that can help you get them back. This fact incentives hackers to target cryptocurrency since they get to keep everything they steal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; The risk of having funds stolen in bitcoin with mobile wallets than with any other type of wallet because it’s always connected to the internet, in arms reach of bad actors. Consider avoiding mobile wallets if you want to maximize security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-difference-between-a-bitcoin-wallet-and-a-physical-wallet&quot;&gt;What is the difference between a bitcoin wallet and a physical wallet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/02-bitcoin-wallets/bitcoin-wallet-physical-wallet-digital-wallet.png&quot; alt=&quot;digital wallet physical wallet&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;60%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With cash, a physical wallet can hold value in your wallet directly. Whereas a bitcoin wallet only ever stores access to your funds on the blockchain via your private keys. This works a bit like your credit or debit card has access to the funds in a bank account. In Bitcoin, your private keys give you access to your fund on the blockchain, but without any physical card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike a physical wallet that has to be carried around, your bitcoin wallet has all the properties of being digital. But because your keys are just data, they sent over the internet or spoken as human-readable words over the phone. Bitcoin is easier to send, but also easier for hackers to steal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-types-of-wallets-are-there&quot;&gt;What types of wallets are there?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are wallets that run on your phone (&lt;strong&gt;mobile wallets&lt;/strong&gt;), wallets that run on your desktop (&lt;strong&gt;desktop wallets&lt;/strong&gt;), and wallets that run in the browser (&lt;strong&gt;web wallets&lt;/strong&gt;). There’s also the more novel paper wallet or brain wallet, that best to just stay away from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-hot-wallets-and-cold-wallets&quot;&gt;What are hot wallets and cold wallets?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile, desktop, and web wallets are all &lt;strong&gt;hot wallets&lt;/strong&gt; because they are connected to the internet, putting them in closer reach of hackers. &lt;strong&gt;Hardware wallets&lt;/strong&gt; are the most secure wallet option because they keep your keys offline and in &lt;strong&gt;cold storage&lt;/strong&gt;, this is why they are also called &lt;strong&gt;cold storage wallets&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are pros and cons to each. Hot wallets are generally more convenient, they tend to have a friendlier user interface, and are easier to use. Cold storage wallets can be a bit of a hassle but a substantially more secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; To prevent hackers from making more money from their side-hustle it’s best practice to avoid using hot wallets for any bitcoin you plan on keeping long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-custodial-and-non-custodial-wallets&quot;&gt;What are custodial and non-custodial wallets?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people start off with their first buy and sell of bitcoin on an exchange, which holds your funds for you in a &lt;strong&gt;custodial wallet&lt;/strong&gt;, where the exchange is taking custody of your private keys. When you move your funds off of an exchange into a wallet you control, you’re using a non-custodial wallet. &lt;strong&gt;Non-custodial wallets&lt;/strong&gt; allow you to store your own private keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;once-i-choose-a-wallet-how-do-i-get-one-and-use-it&quot;&gt;Once I choose a wallet, how do I get one and use it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 1: Choose which wallet app you’re going to use, then download the software. If you’re using a mobile device you can download a mobile app from the app store.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 2: Open the software to create a wallet, private key, and mnemonic recovery phrase.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 3: Write down your mnemonic and store it someplace safe.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 4: Create a receive address and QR code. At this point you’re ready to receive bitcoin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 5: Share your wallet address or QR code to accept bitcoin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you’re set up with a Bitcoin BTC wallet and not a Bitcoin Cash BCH cryptocurrency wallet. Bitcoin Cash is not Bitcoin, but Bitcoin Cash payments look a lot like bitcoin and it can potentially be a very expensive mistake to confuse the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SECOND TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; From a new user perspective, the experience of using bitcoin can feel like other online wallets or online payment methods. Yes, we use Bitcoin from a digital wallet but Bitcoin is also a &lt;strong&gt;digital currency&lt;/strong&gt;. The properties of Bitcoin isn’t the same as loyalty cards, Apple pay, or even Samsung pay. Bitcoin may be the 2089 future of field communication NFC contactless payments, but bitcoin wallets have different properties from other mobile payment apps users are used to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;picture&quot;=&gt;&quot;/img/about/kiara-bickers.jpg&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;kiarabickers&quot;}</name></author><summary type="html">What is the best bitcoin wallet in 2020? Bitcoin Core is the best wallet available. If there was an official bitcoin wallet this would be it, and it’s free. Bitcoin Core may not be the most user friendly since it’s for the more advanced “power users”, but it’s the highest performing full node you can run, and it’s the only way to use Bitcoin peer-to-peer. Bitcoin Core can also be used with a hardware wallet or privacy wallet. So what is the best bitcoin wallet for beginners? The trust is that there isn’t a single best wallet it is about trade-offs. Welcome to the complete beginners’ guide to wallets! I’ll start with the basics. What is the difference between a bitcoin app and other payment apps? With most major payment apps every transaction is covered by the bank’s fraud protection. Meaning that if you someone steals your funds, or if you have been a victim of fraud, you have a company waiting in the wings to bail you out. This is not the case with cryptocurrency. With any bitcoin wallet, you’re taking complete control of your funds. This means also that if you lose those funds there is no one that can help you get them back. This fact incentives hackers to target cryptocurrency since they get to keep everything they steal. TIP: The risk of having funds stolen in bitcoin with mobile wallets than with any other type of wallet because it’s always connected to the internet, in arms reach of bad actors. Consider avoiding mobile wallets if you want to maximize security. What is the difference between a bitcoin wallet and a physical wallet? With cash, a physical wallet can hold value in your wallet directly. Whereas a bitcoin wallet only ever stores access to your funds on the blockchain via your private keys. This works a bit like your credit or debit card has access to the funds in a bank account. In Bitcoin, your private keys give you access to your fund on the blockchain, but without any physical card. Unlike a physical wallet that has to be carried around, your bitcoin wallet has all the properties of being digital. But because your keys are just data, they sent over the internet or spoken as human-readable words over the phone. Bitcoin is easier to send, but also easier for hackers to steal. What types of wallets are there? There are wallets that run on your phone (mobile wallets), wallets that run on your desktop (desktop wallets), and wallets that run in the browser (web wallets). There’s also the more novel paper wallet or brain wallet, that best to just stay away from. What are hot wallets and cold wallets? Mobile, desktop, and web wallets are all hot wallets because they are connected to the internet, putting them in closer reach of hackers. Hardware wallets are the most secure wallet option because they keep your keys offline and in cold storage, this is why they are also called cold storage wallets. There are pros and cons to each. Hot wallets are generally more convenient, they tend to have a friendlier user interface, and are easier to use. Cold storage wallets can be a bit of a hassle but a substantially more secure. TIP: To prevent hackers from making more money from their side-hustle it’s best practice to avoid using hot wallets for any bitcoin you plan on keeping long term. What are custodial and non-custodial wallets? Most people start off with their first buy and sell of bitcoin on an exchange, which holds your funds for you in a custodial wallet, where the exchange is taking custody of your private keys. When you move your funds off of an exchange into a wallet you control, you’re using a non-custodial wallet. Non-custodial wallets allow you to store your own private keys. Once I choose a wallet, how do I get one and use it? Step 1: Choose which wallet app you’re going to use, then download the software. If you’re using a mobile device you can download a mobile app from the app store. Step 2: Open the software to create a wallet, private key, and mnemonic recovery phrase. Step 3: Write down your mnemonic and store it someplace safe. Step 4: Create a receive address and QR code. At this point you’re ready to receive bitcoin. Step 5: Share your wallet address or QR code to accept bitcoin. TIP: Make sure you’re set up with a Bitcoin BTC wallet and not a Bitcoin Cash BCH cryptocurrency wallet. Bitcoin Cash is not Bitcoin, but Bitcoin Cash payments look a lot like bitcoin and it can potentially be a very expensive mistake to confuse the two. SECOND TIP: From a new user perspective, the experience of using bitcoin can feel like other online wallets or online payment methods. Yes, we use Bitcoin from a digital wallet but Bitcoin is also a digital currency. The properties of Bitcoin isn’t the same as loyalty cards, Apple pay, or even Samsung pay. Bitcoin may be the 2089 future of field communication NFC contactless payments, but bitcoin wallets have different properties from other mobile payment apps users are used to.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/22-choosing-a-bitcoin-wallet.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bitcoin Private Keys: Getting Started With The Basics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/16/bitcoin-public-private-keys" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bitcoin Private Keys: Getting Started With The Basics" /><published>2020-05-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/16/bitcoin-public-private-keys</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/16/bitcoin-public-private-keys">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bitcoin network uses cryptography to create a key pair that controls access to bitcoin on the blockchain. Each bitcoin key pair consists of a public and private key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-difference-between-private-and-public-keys&quot;&gt;What is the difference between private and public keys?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People can over-complicate explanations by trying to explain digital signatures, signing transactions, and wallet import formats. But the truth is most users don’t need any of this detail to understand the basics of how keys work in Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can think of public-key cryptography as a lock, but with two keys instead of one:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/01-bitcoin-keys/bitcoin-privatekey-publickey-lock.png&quot; alt=&quot;bitcoin private key public key bitcoin clarity&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;bitcoin private key&lt;/strong&gt; is simply a large (256 bits) secret number that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;allows bitcoin to be unlocked and sent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This key authorizes the bitcoin transaction. It’s called a private key because it is meant to be kept private and not shown to other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;bitcoin public key&lt;/strong&gt; is another large number but &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;allows bitcoin to be locked and received&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. A bitcoin address is a hashed smaller version of the private key. It’s called a public key because it is meant to be shared publicly and enables you to receive funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although you don’t need to understand cryptomagic to believe that it works, sometimes understanding the &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; is the key to being able to trust it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-is-the-private-key-related-to-the-public-key&quot;&gt;How is the private key related to the public key?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two keys (or numbers) are related mathematically on the secp256k1 elliptic curve. The private key is a randomly generated number plotted on the curve, and the public key is a corresponding point on that curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real point of this magical curve is that it creates &lt;strong&gt;trap door functionality&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning that once we generate the first point on the curve (the private key) the corresponding second point (public key) is easily found but impossible to find in the opposite direction. If you have the private key you always have the public key, but if you have the public key it’s mathematically impossible to find the private key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-is-the-public-key-related-to-the-address&quot;&gt;How is the public key related to the address?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Addresses are smaller (hashed version) of public keys:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/01-bitcoin-keys/bitcoin-privatekey-publickey-address.png&quot; alt=&quot;bitcoin address public key bitcoin clarity&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;60%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public keys start with a 1 , 3 or bc1 because they come in different formats. There are uncompressed public keys, compressed public keys, and wif formats. But what’s important to understand is that when you’re providing someone with a public address (or QR code) you’re giving them the ability to lock bitcoin on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-are-bitcoin-keys-and-addresses-generated&quot;&gt;How are bitcoin keys and addresses generated?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed//QR1HZYod7Vs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bitcoin wallet software generates your wallet file, addresses, and keys. The private is generated from a part of the software that is specially designed to be able to handle big numbers and generate them at random.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a feel for this you can play around with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitaddress.org/bitaddress.org-v3.3.0-SHA256-dec17c07685e1870960903d8f58090475b25af946fe95a734f88408cef4aa194.html&quot;&gt;bitaddress.org&lt;/a&gt;, but don’t use for any real keys you plan on using, this is just a tool for understanding. For keys that you plan on using, you’ll want to use Bitcoin Core or a hardware wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-many-private-keys-are-there&quot;&gt;How many private keys are there?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There a lot, about 10 million million million million million million million million, or 115792089237316195423570985008687907852837564279074904382605163141518161494336 possible private keys to be exact. The number of possible keys is so large, that security of bitcoin relies on the assumption that no one will ever randomly generate the same two private keys twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-seed-phrase-or-mnemonic-recovery&quot;&gt;What is a seed phrase or mnemonic recovery?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A mnemonic phrase is a private key in a different form:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/01-bitcoin-keys/bitcoin-privatekey-generation-mnemonic-recovery.png&quot; alt=&quot;bitcoin mnemonic recovery phrase bitcoin clarity&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way numbers can be expressed as words (zero) and numerical digits (0), keys are just a really long string of numbers that have the same properties. Instead of using the word expression of the random number, the seed phrase uses a list of 12 or 24 random words to represent the random number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the mnemonic is to convert currency into human-readable words. So that the transfer of value can be written on to paper, or spoken over a cell phone and easily shared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add some security a password can also be added to the phrase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-best-way-to-store-private-keys-safely&quot;&gt;What is the best way to store private keys safely?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most secure way to store private keys safely is offline in cold storage, on a dedicated hardware device with your recovery mnemonic stored separately.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;picture&quot;=&gt;&quot;/img/about/kiara-bickers.jpg&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;kiarabickers&quot;}</name></author><summary type="html">The Bitcoin network uses cryptography to create a key pair that controls access to bitcoin on the blockchain. Each bitcoin key pair consists of a public and private key. What is the difference between private and public keys? People can over-complicate explanations by trying to explain digital signatures, signing transactions, and wallet import formats. But the truth is most users don’t need any of this detail to understand the basics of how keys work in Bitcoin. You can think of public-key cryptography as a lock, but with two keys instead of one: A bitcoin private key is simply a large (256 bits) secret number that allows bitcoin to be unlocked and sent. This key authorizes the bitcoin transaction. It’s called a private key because it is meant to be kept private and not shown to other people. A bitcoin public key is another large number but allows bitcoin to be locked and received. A bitcoin address is a hashed smaller version of the private key. It’s called a public key because it is meant to be shared publicly and enables you to receive funds. Although you don’t need to understand cryptomagic to believe that it works, sometimes understanding the how is the key to being able to trust it. How is the private key related to the public key? These two keys (or numbers) are related mathematically on the secp256k1 elliptic curve. The private key is a randomly generated number plotted on the curve, and the public key is a corresponding point on that curve. The real point of this magical curve is that it creates trap door functionality, meaning that once we generate the first point on the curve (the private key) the corresponding second point (public key) is easily found but impossible to find in the opposite direction. If you have the private key you always have the public key, but if you have the public key it’s mathematically impossible to find the private key. How is the public key related to the address? Addresses are smaller (hashed version) of public keys: Public keys start with a 1 , 3 or bc1 because they come in different formats. There are uncompressed public keys, compressed public keys, and wif formats. But what’s important to understand is that when you’re providing someone with a public address (or QR code) you’re giving them the ability to lock bitcoin on your behalf. How are bitcoin keys and addresses generated? The bitcoin wallet software generates your wallet file, addresses, and keys. The private is generated from a part of the software that is specially designed to be able to handle big numbers and generate them at random. To get a feel for this you can play around with bitaddress.org, but don’t use for any real keys you plan on using, this is just a tool for understanding. For keys that you plan on using, you’ll want to use Bitcoin Core or a hardware wallet. How many private keys are there? There a lot, about 10 million million million million million million million million, or 115792089237316195423570985008687907852837564279074904382605163141518161494336 possible private keys to be exact. The number of possible keys is so large, that security of bitcoin relies on the assumption that no one will ever randomly generate the same two private keys twice. What is a seed phrase or mnemonic recovery? A mnemonic phrase is a private key in a different form: In the same way numbers can be expressed as words (zero) and numerical digits (0), keys are just a really long string of numbers that have the same properties. Instead of using the word expression of the random number, the seed phrase uses a list of 12 or 24 random words to represent the random number. The purpose of the mnemonic is to convert currency into human-readable words. So that the transfer of value can be written on to paper, or spoken over a cell phone and easily shared. To add some security a password can also be added to the phrase. What is the best way to store private keys safely? The most secure way to store private keys safely is offline in cold storage, on a dedicated hardware device with your recovery mnemonic stored separately.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/01-bitcoin-keys.jpg" /></entry></feed>