<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-16T16:32:40-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/index.xml</id><title type="html">Kiara Bickers - Official Site | How to Get Started With Bitcoin</title><subtitle>Bitcoin Clarity explains what Bitcoin is, why it works, and if it can work for you.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What You Need to Know About Bitcoin Hashrate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/23/what-you-need-to-know-about-hashrate" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What You Need to Know About Bitcoin Hashrate" /><published>2019-10-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-10-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/23/what-you-need-to-know-about-hashrate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/23/what-you-need-to-know-about-hashrate">&lt;p&gt;What is the Bitcoin hashrate? How is it measured? What does a high or low network hashrate indicate for the rest of the Bitcoin network?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;SUMMARY:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several weeks ago the price of Bitcoin crashed from $10,000 to $8,000 dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The perception was that the Bitcoin hashrate had crashed 30%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investors view the total network hashrate as a bid for miners to buy the bitcoins being released in the next block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High hashrate tends to move the price up. Low hashrate tends to move the price down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But because people misunderstand how hashrate is measured investors saw a “crash” in hashrate that didn’t reflect reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s video, I show you what hashrate is, AND how it’s measured, so you understand why this crash wasn’t real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out and let me know what you think in the comments?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heres-what-i-cover&quot;&gt;HERE’S WHAT I COVER:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What hashrate is. (The total number of hashes being computed by the miners in the network)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How you can instead think of the blockchain as a timechain, or a decentralized clock. Why that clock needs to keep time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The 3 primary types of clocks and how Bitcoins timechain is different.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How the timing of this decentralized clock is measured with blocks and regulated by proof-of-work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why the blockchain is trustless. (It doesn’t check any 3rd party source of time.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How the blockchain is permissionless. (Miners are allowed to join or drop off at any time.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why the property of permissionless, makes regulating the timing of new blocks tricky. And how it’s controlled by a feedback control loop.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Your Expanded Understanding!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kiara Bickers&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kiara bickers</name></author><category term="fed" /><category term="economics" /><summary type="html">What is the Bitcoin hashrate? How is it measured? What does a high or low network hashrate indicate for the rest of the Bitcoin network? SUMMARY: Several weeks ago the price of Bitcoin crashed from $10,000 to $8,000 dollars. The perception was that the Bitcoin hashrate had crashed 30%. Investors view the total network hashrate as a bid for miners to buy the bitcoins being released in the next block. High hashrate tends to move the price up. Low hashrate tends to move the price down. But because people misunderstand how hashrate is measured investors saw a “crash” in hashrate that didn’t reflect reality. In today’s video, I show you what hashrate is, AND how it’s measured, so you understand why this crash wasn’t real. Check it out and let me know what you think in the comments? HERE’S WHAT I COVER: What hashrate is. (The total number of hashes being computed by the miners in the network) How you can instead think of the blockchain as a timechain, or a decentralized clock. Why that clock needs to keep time. The 3 primary types of clocks and how Bitcoins timechain is different. How the timing of this decentralized clock is measured with blocks and regulated by proof-of-work. Why the blockchain is trustless. (It doesn’t check any 3rd party source of time.) How the blockchain is permissionless. (Miners are allowed to join or drop off at any time.) Why the property of permissionless, makes regulating the timing of new blocks tricky. And how it’s controlled by a feedback control loop. To Your Expanded Understanding! Kiara Bickers</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/what-you-need-to-know-about-hashrate.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Federal Reserve Is Expanding Its Balance Sheet</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/10/federal-reserve-expanding-its-balance-sheet" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Federal Reserve Is Expanding Its Balance Sheet" /><published>2019-10-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-10-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/10/federal-reserve-expanding-its-balance-sheet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/10/10/federal-reserve-expanding-its-balance-sheet">&lt;p&gt;What is the fed balance sheet? What does it mean to expand it? And how does that affect us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;SUMMARY:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why are we hearing about the federal reserve expanding its balance sheet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is the FEDs balance sheet different from the average businesses? What typical constraints are they not limited by?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way money is created in the economy isn’t magic, although there is good reason that it appears to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every investor watches what the FED does, and aims to derive some cause and effect from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actions of the FED don’t happen for no reason, they take deliberate moves that they believe will have the greatest impact on the economy, consumer prices, and jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But realistically, the actions of the FED also affect every other part of market (stocks, commodities, gold, and crypto) and that’s why investors follow their every move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s video I show you what it means for the FED to be expanding its balance sheet, when is full-blown quantitive easing, and when is it not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out and let me know what you think in the comments?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heres-what-i-cover&quot;&gt;HERE’S WHAT I COVER:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How does the average business balance sheet compare with the Federal Reserves’ balance sheet?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How does consumer and investor spending differ from Federal Reserve spending?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How are US Treasury assets are a lot like consumer credit cards?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The 3 primary types of US Treasury assets, what they are and how they differ from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why the Federal Reserve is buying US Treasury assets, and why we can’t ignore it!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why people are confusing the FED expanding its balance sheet for quantitative easing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How to see the details of this central bank maneuver and judge for yourself on what this move really means.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Your Expanded Understanding!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kiara Bickers&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kiara bickers</name></author><category term="fed" /><category term="economics" /><summary type="html">What is the fed balance sheet? What does it mean to expand it? And how does that affect us? SUMMARY: Why are we hearing about the federal reserve expanding its balance sheet? How is the FEDs balance sheet different from the average businesses? What typical constraints are they not limited by? The way money is created in the economy isn’t magic, although there is good reason that it appears to be. Every investor watches what the FED does, and aims to derive some cause and effect from it. The actions of the FED don’t happen for no reason, they take deliberate moves that they believe will have the greatest impact on the economy, consumer prices, and jobs. But realistically, the actions of the FED also affect every other part of market (stocks, commodities, gold, and crypto) and that’s why investors follow their every move. In today’s video I show you what it means for the FED to be expanding its balance sheet, when is full-blown quantitive easing, and when is it not. Check it out and let me know what you think in the comments? HERE’S WHAT I COVER: How does the average business balance sheet compare with the Federal Reserves’ balance sheet? How does consumer and investor spending differ from Federal Reserve spending? How are US Treasury assets are a lot like consumer credit cards? The 3 primary types of US Treasury assets, what they are and how they differ from each other. Why the Federal Reserve is buying US Treasury assets, and why we can’t ignore it! Why people are confusing the FED expanding its balance sheet for quantitative easing. How to see the details of this central bank maneuver and judge for yourself on what this move really means. To Your Expanded Understanding! Kiara Bickers</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/federal-reserve-expanding-its-balance-sheet.png" /></entry></feed>