<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-15T09:32:40-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/index.xml</id><title type="html">Kiara Bickers - Official Site | Bitcoin Clarity</title><subtitle>Bitcoin Clarity: The Complete Beginners Guide by Kiara Bickers Explains; What is Bitcoin? How Does Bitcoin Work? How to Understand It Easily With Mental Models.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What is Bitcoin and How Does it Work? [Easy Understanding]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/21/what-is-bitcoin" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Bitcoin and How Does it Work? [Easy Understanding]" /><published>2020-05-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/21/what-is-bitcoin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/21/what-is-bitcoin">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asking this question the typical answer you’re going to get is likely to be about bitcoins mysterious creator Satoshi Nakamoto, how there are only 21 million bitcoins that will ever be created, and how to buy bitcoin before the price goes to the moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we’re not we’re here for the hype, I’m going to give it to you straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, magic internet money can be a bit complex but it doesn’t need to be complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-bitcoin&quot;&gt;What is Bitcoin?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/strong&gt; is a network of computers (or nodes) that each record the transfer of value over a shared public ledger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each computer in the Bitcoin network that runs the full bitcoin software is referred to as a full node maintains a copy of the ledger. This ledger is called the blockchain, and the value that is transferred on it—is denominated in bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-bitcoin&quot;&gt;What is a bitcoin?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin with a capital refers to the protocol and lowercase b refers to the digital unit that is the medium of exchange on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/03-what-is-bitcoin/blockchain-bitcoin-from-bitcoin-clarity.png&quot; alt=&quot;bitcoin block from bitcoin clarity&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;75%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This network was first launched in 2009, by the pseudonyms creator Satoshi Nakamoto. It is the first cryptocurrency, and the first digital currency to successfully implement the ability to use public-key cryptography for sending and receiving (or locking and unlocking) transactions instead of its traditional use in encrypting and decrypting messages. &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2020/05/16/what-is-a-bitcoin-private-key&quot;&gt;Private keys&lt;/a&gt; stored in &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2020/05/17/what-is-a-bitcoin-wallet&quot;&gt;Bitcoin wallets&lt;/a&gt; authorize the transfer of bitcoin for transactions created on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To really understand Bitcoin we have to ask the question that cypherpunks were asking themselves before it was created. How do we create a way to transfer value securely over the insecure internet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time this was a difficult problem to solve because there was no known way to get computers distributed all over the world, to come to an agreed-upon timestamp and order for transactions to be received. If you read the original Bitcoin white paper, you’ll see that bitcoin was never referred to as a blockchain but instead it was referred to as a decentralized timestamp server or timechain. Bitcoin miners and full nodes create a system capable of keeping time without a third party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-blockchain-in-simple-terms&quot;&gt;What is the Blockchain in simple terms?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;blockchain&lt;/strong&gt; is a digital ledger that stores its history of transactions in blocks that are linked (and hashed) together to make a provably unbreakable chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because all of this information is digital the concept of blocks and chains isn’t literal, transactions are grouped together in data structures called “blocks”, and “chained” together by a hash function. This is why people use the words “block” and “chain refer to the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-block-bitcoin-block&quot;&gt;What is a block (Bitcoin block)?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;block&lt;/strong&gt; is a group of transactions that have been confirmed at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the raw data for a block in the blockchain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/03-what-is-bitcoin/bitcoin-block-from-bitcoin-clarity.png&quot; alt=&quot;bitcoin block from bitcoin clarity&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;75%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blocks are where Bitcoin stores data. The bitcoin block structure is comprised of: a version, previous block hash, a Merkle root, timestamp, difficulty, nonce, transaction count, and most importantly the transaction list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every ledger needs to properly order transactions. If I’m paying you for a good or service we need a way of knowing when the money has moved from wallet to yours. We need to know when the funds are not mine anymore so that you can legally spend them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But because this network is made up of computers all over the world network solving this problem this is a bit complicated. Even if transactions happened at “exactly the same time,” when two computers are in opposite parts of the world they are likely to disagree on the order of those transactions, because the news of each transaction travels at different speeds and arrives at different times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wwu7JED2tnM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blockchain is made up of blocks that group transactions together. All transactions that are grouped in the same block, we say occurred at the same time. This gives the blockchain a final order for confirmed transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-shared-public-ledger-bitcoin-ledger&quot;&gt;What is a shared public ledger (Bitcoin ledger)?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The peer-to-peer network of Bitcoin users:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/03-what-is-bitcoin/blockchain-full-nodes-from-bitcoin-clarity.png&quot; alt=&quot;bitcoin full nodes from bitcoin clarity&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;60%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The public shared ledger is the record of all the bitcoin transactions on the blockchain. Because the ledger is stored by each of the independent full nodes in the network, we say that the ledger is “shared”. Instead of being shared, another way to think of it is that &lt;strong&gt;all of the ledgers are synchronized to the same state&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every computer that runs the full bitcoin software (every “full node”) validates every transaction in the network to check that each is conforming to the same set of rules. The rules in Bitcoin are things like: users can’t spend funds they don’t have the private keys to, and miners can never be more than 21 million coins. Each cryptocurrency has its own ledger, with its own set of rules, so not all blockchains have the same properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Bitcoin is not centralized in any way, it’s not owned by a company or controlled by any organization. Payments that occur on this ledger can’t be stopped or censored. Bitcoin code is open-source, transactions on the network are public and permissionless, meaning that there is no asking an authority for permission, anyone who chooses to use it can. Transactions are processed trustlessly, without any middle-man or third party processor, which frees users from the need of banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ymAYDdffKXM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of having a single shared ledger for global transactions to take place was a massive innovation in cryptography and accounting. This ledger allows users to transfer value securely and peer-to-peer, and without censorship, which is not something that could be done with any previous payment system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-bitcoin-real-money&quot;&gt;Is Bitcoin real money?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money is defined as a medium of exchange, typically in the form of coins or paper, being issued by a government or bank. Because bitcoin isn’t bank or government-issued it’s more accurately defined as an asset, commodity, or currency, hence the term crypto “currency”.  Bitcoin is a medium of exchange and a store of value, but many also people use it as a tool for speculation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government currency has one distinct advantage over Bitcoin: the government can create a demand for their currency, whereas the price of Bitcoin is put in the unsteady hands of the market. Any instability in the economy tends to mean that price of Bitcoin spikes up and down quickly as investors moving their funds into and out the asset looking for something that can hold their value. Few people really understand what Bitcoin is or what the blockchain is good for.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;picture&quot;=&gt;&quot;/img/about/kiara-bickers.jpg&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;kiarabickers&quot;}</name></author><summary type="html">When asking this question the typical answer you’re going to get is likely to be about bitcoins mysterious creator Satoshi Nakamoto, how there are only 21 million bitcoins that will ever be created, and how to buy bitcoin before the price goes to the moon. But we’re not we’re here for the hype, I’m going to give it to you straight. Yes, magic internet money can be a bit complex but it doesn’t need to be complicated. What is Bitcoin? Bitcoin is a network of computers (or nodes) that each record the transfer of value over a shared public ledger. Each computer in the Bitcoin network that runs the full bitcoin software is referred to as a full node maintains a copy of the ledger. This ledger is called the blockchain, and the value that is transferred on it—is denominated in bitcoin. What is a bitcoin? Bitcoin with a capital refers to the protocol and lowercase b refers to the digital unit that is the medium of exchange on the blockchain. This network was first launched in 2009, by the pseudonyms creator Satoshi Nakamoto. It is the first cryptocurrency, and the first digital currency to successfully implement the ability to use public-key cryptography for sending and receiving (or locking and unlocking) transactions instead of its traditional use in encrypting and decrypting messages. Private keys stored in Bitcoin wallets authorize the transfer of bitcoin for transactions created on the blockchain. To really understand Bitcoin we have to ask the question that cypherpunks were asking themselves before it was created. How do we create a way to transfer value securely over the insecure internet? At the time this was a difficult problem to solve because there was no known way to get computers distributed all over the world, to come to an agreed-upon timestamp and order for transactions to be received. If you read the original Bitcoin white paper, you’ll see that bitcoin was never referred to as a blockchain but instead it was referred to as a decentralized timestamp server or timechain. Bitcoin miners and full nodes create a system capable of keeping time without a third party. What is the Blockchain in simple terms? The blockchain is a digital ledger that stores its history of transactions in blocks that are linked (and hashed) together to make a provably unbreakable chain. Because all of this information is digital the concept of blocks and chains isn’t literal, transactions are grouped together in data structures called “blocks”, and “chained” together by a hash function. This is why people use the words “block” and “chain refer to the blockchain. What is a block (Bitcoin block)? A block is a group of transactions that have been confirmed at the same time. Take a look at the raw data for a block in the blockchain: Blocks are where Bitcoin stores data. The bitcoin block structure is comprised of: a version, previous block hash, a Merkle root, timestamp, difficulty, nonce, transaction count, and most importantly the transaction list. Every ledger needs to properly order transactions. If I’m paying you for a good or service we need a way of knowing when the money has moved from wallet to yours. We need to know when the funds are not mine anymore so that you can legally spend them. But because this network is made up of computers all over the world network solving this problem this is a bit complicated. Even if transactions happened at “exactly the same time,” when two computers are in opposite parts of the world they are likely to disagree on the order of those transactions, because the news of each transaction travels at different speeds and arrives at different times. The blockchain is made up of blocks that group transactions together. All transactions that are grouped in the same block, we say occurred at the same time. This gives the blockchain a final order for confirmed transactions. What is a shared public ledger (Bitcoin ledger)? The peer-to-peer network of Bitcoin users: The public shared ledger is the record of all the bitcoin transactions on the blockchain. Because the ledger is stored by each of the independent full nodes in the network, we say that the ledger is “shared”. Instead of being shared, another way to think of it is that all of the ledgers are synchronized to the same state. Every computer that runs the full bitcoin software (every “full node”) validates every transaction in the network to check that each is conforming to the same set of rules. The rules in Bitcoin are things like: users can’t spend funds they don’t have the private keys to, and miners can never be more than 21 million coins. Each cryptocurrency has its own ledger, with its own set of rules, so not all blockchains have the same properties. Because Bitcoin is not centralized in any way, it’s not owned by a company or controlled by any organization. Payments that occur on this ledger can’t be stopped or censored. Bitcoin code is open-source, transactions on the network are public and permissionless, meaning that there is no asking an authority for permission, anyone who chooses to use it can. Transactions are processed trustlessly, without any middle-man or third party processor, which frees users from the need of banks. The concept of having a single shared ledger for global transactions to take place was a massive innovation in cryptography and accounting. This ledger allows users to transfer value securely and peer-to-peer, and without censorship, which is not something that could be done with any previous payment system. Is Bitcoin real money? Money is defined as a medium of exchange, typically in the form of coins or paper, being issued by a government or bank. Because bitcoin isn’t bank or government-issued it’s more accurately defined as an asset, commodity, or currency, hence the term crypto “currency”. Bitcoin is a medium of exchange and a store of value, but many also people use it as a tool for speculation. Government currency has one distinct advantage over Bitcoin: the government can create a demand for their currency, whereas the price of Bitcoin is put in the unsteady hands of the market. Any instability in the economy tends to mean that price of Bitcoin spikes up and down quickly as investors moving their funds into and out the asset looking for something that can hold their value. Few people really understand what Bitcoin is or what the blockchain is good for.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/04-timechain-not-blockchain.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/04-timechain-not-blockchain.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bitcoin Wallets: Getting Started With The Basics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/17/what-is-a-bitcoin-wallet" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bitcoin Wallets: Getting Started With The Basics" /><published>2020-05-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/17/what-is-a-bitcoin-wallet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/17/what-is-a-bitcoin-wallet">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-bitcoin-wallet&quot;&gt;What is a bitcoin wallet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, a &lt;strong&gt;wallet&lt;/strong&gt; is a program that stores your private keys. There many different types of bitcoin and cryptocurrency wallets, all with different trade-offs, risks, and security profiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-bitcoin-wallets-work&quot;&gt;How do bitcoin wallets work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because bitcoin only exists on the blockchain, wallets don’t technically store your bitcoin. Your &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2020/05/16/what-is-a-bitcoin-private-key&quot;&gt;private keys&lt;/a&gt; provide access to your bitcoin and your wallet stores your private keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wallets also manage the derived public keys, bitcoin addresses, and QR codes that enable users to send and receive bitcoin. For key management wallet software all implement different versions of hierarchical deterministic keys (BIP32) which organizes the parent and child keys into a hierarchical structure, where the mnemonic recovery can seed the root of the wallet and all of its associated keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-best-bitcoin-wallet-in-2020&quot;&gt;What is the best bitcoin wallet in 2020?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/02-bitcoin-wallets/bitcoin-core-screeshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;bitcoin core screeshot&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoincore.org/en/download/&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Core&lt;/a&gt; is the best wallet available. If there was an official bitcoin wallet this would be it, and it’s free. Bitcoin Core may not be the most user friendly since it’s for the more advanced “power users”, but it’s the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lopp.net/bitcoin-node-performance-sync-tests/&quot;&gt;highest performing&lt;/a&gt; full node you can run, and it’s the only way to use Bitcoin peer-to-peer. Bitcoin Core can also be used with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin-core/HWI&quot;&gt;hardware wallet&lt;/a&gt; or a privacy wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-the-best-bitcoin-wallet-for-beginners&quot;&gt;So what is the best bitcoin wallet for beginners?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that there isn’t a single best single choice it’s all about trade-offs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the complete beginners’ guide to wallets! I’ll start with the basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-difference-between-a-bitcoin-app-and-other-payment-apps&quot;&gt;What is the difference between a bitcoin app and other payment apps?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With most major payment apps every transaction is covered by the bank’s fraud protection. Meaning that if you someone steals your funds, or if you have been a victim of fraud, you have a company waiting in the wings to bail you out. This is not the case with cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With any bitcoin wallet, you’re taking complete control of your funds. This means also that if you lose those funds there is no one that can help you get them back. This fact incentives hackers to target cryptocurrency since they get to keep everything they steal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; The risk of having funds stolen with bitcoin is greater than any other type of wallet because it’s typically connected to the internet, in arms reach of bad actors. Consider avoiding mobile wallets if you want to maximize security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-difference-between-a-bitcoin-wallet-and-a-physical-wallet&quot;&gt;What is the difference between a bitcoin wallet and a physical wallet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/02-bitcoin-wallets/bitcoin-wallet-physical-wallet-digital-wallet.png&quot; alt=&quot;digital wallet physical wallet&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;60%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With cash, a physical wallet can hold value in your wallet directly. Whereas a bitcoin wallet only ever stores access to your funds on the blockchain via your private keys. This works a bit like your credit or debit card has access to the funds in a bank account. In Bitcoin, your private keys give you access to your fund on the blockchain, but without any physical card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike a physical wallet that has to be carried around, your bitcoin wallet has all the properties of being digital. But because your keys are just data, they sent over the internet or spoken as human-readable words over the phone. Bitcoin is easier to send, but also easier for hackers to steal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-types-of-wallets-are-there&quot;&gt;What types of wallets are there?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are wallets that run on your phone (mobile wallet), wallets that run on your desktop (desktop wallet), and wallets that run in the browser (web wallet). There’s also the more novel paper wallet or brain wallet, that best to just stay away from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-hot-wallets-and-cold-wallets&quot;&gt;What are hot wallets and cold wallets?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile, desktop, and web wallets are all hot wallets because they are connected to the internet, putting them in closer reach of hackers. Hardware wallets are the most secure wallet option because they keep your keys offline and in cold storage, this is why they are also called cold storage wallets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are pros and cons to each. Hot wallets are generally more convenient, they tend to have a friendlier user interface and are easier to use. Cold wallets can be a bit of a hassle but are substantially more secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; To prevent hackers from making more money from their side-hustle it’s best practice to avoid using hot wallets for any bitcoin you plan on keeping long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-custodial-and-non-custodial-wallets&quot;&gt;What are custodial and non-custodial wallets?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people start off with their first buy and sell of bitcoin on an exchange, which holds your funds for you in a custodial wallet, where the exchange is taking custody of your private keys. When you move your funds off of an exchange into a wallet you control, you’re using a non-custodial wallet that allows you to store your own keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I choose a wallet . . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-i-get-a-bitcoin-wallet-and-use-it&quot;&gt;How do I get a Bitcoin wallet and use it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 1: Choose which wallet app you’re going to use, then download the software. If you’re using a mobile device you can download a mobile app from the app store.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 2: Open the software to create a wallet, private key, and mnemonic recovery phrase.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 3: Write down your mnemonic and store it someplace safe.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 4: Create a receive address and QR code. At this point you’re ready to receive bitcoin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Step 5: Share your wallet address or QR code to accept bitcoin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you’re set up with a Bitcoin BTC wallet and not one that is intended for Bitcoin Cash BCH. Bitcoin Cash is not Bitcoin, but Bitcoin Cash payments look a lot like bitcoin and it can potentially be a very expensive mistake to confuse the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SECOND TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; From a new user perspective, the experience of using bitcoin can feel like other online wallets or online payment methods. Yes, Bitcoin is an online payment system, but Bitcoin is also a digital currency. The properties of Bitcoin isn’t the same as loyalty cards, Apple pay, or even Samsung pay. Bitcoin may be the 2089 future of field communication NFC contactless payments, but bitcoin wallets have different properties from other mobile payment apps users are used to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;picture&quot;=&gt;&quot;/img/about/kiara-bickers.jpg&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;kiarabickers&quot;}</name></author><summary type="html">What is a bitcoin wallet? Simply put, a wallet is a program that stores your private keys. There many different types of bitcoin and cryptocurrency wallets, all with different trade-offs, risks, and security profiles. How do bitcoin wallets work? Because bitcoin only exists on the blockchain, wallets don’t technically store your bitcoin. Your private keys provide access to your bitcoin and your wallet stores your private keys. Wallets also manage the derived public keys, bitcoin addresses, and QR codes that enable users to send and receive bitcoin. For key management wallet software all implement different versions of hierarchical deterministic keys (BIP32) which organizes the parent and child keys into a hierarchical structure, where the mnemonic recovery can seed the root of the wallet and all of its associated keys. What is the best bitcoin wallet in 2020? Bitcoin Core is the best wallet available. If there was an official bitcoin wallet this would be it, and it’s free. Bitcoin Core may not be the most user friendly since it’s for the more advanced “power users”, but it’s the highest performing full node you can run, and it’s the only way to use Bitcoin peer-to-peer. Bitcoin Core can also be used with a hardware wallet or a privacy wallet. So what is the best bitcoin wallet for beginners? The truth is that there isn’t a single best single choice it’s all about trade-offs. Welcome to the complete beginners’ guide to wallets! I’ll start with the basics. What is the difference between a bitcoin app and other payment apps? With most major payment apps every transaction is covered by the bank’s fraud protection. Meaning that if you someone steals your funds, or if you have been a victim of fraud, you have a company waiting in the wings to bail you out. This is not the case with cryptocurrency. With any bitcoin wallet, you’re taking complete control of your funds. This means also that if you lose those funds there is no one that can help you get them back. This fact incentives hackers to target cryptocurrency since they get to keep everything they steal. TIP: The risk of having funds stolen with bitcoin is greater than any other type of wallet because it’s typically connected to the internet, in arms reach of bad actors. Consider avoiding mobile wallets if you want to maximize security. What is the difference between a bitcoin wallet and a physical wallet? With cash, a physical wallet can hold value in your wallet directly. Whereas a bitcoin wallet only ever stores access to your funds on the blockchain via your private keys. This works a bit like your credit or debit card has access to the funds in a bank account. In Bitcoin, your private keys give you access to your fund on the blockchain, but without any physical card. Unlike a physical wallet that has to be carried around, your bitcoin wallet has all the properties of being digital. But because your keys are just data, they sent over the internet or spoken as human-readable words over the phone. Bitcoin is easier to send, but also easier for hackers to steal. What types of wallets are there? There are wallets that run on your phone (mobile wallet), wallets that run on your desktop (desktop wallet), and wallets that run in the browser (web wallet). There’s also the more novel paper wallet or brain wallet, that best to just stay away from. What are hot wallets and cold wallets? Mobile, desktop, and web wallets are all hot wallets because they are connected to the internet, putting them in closer reach of hackers. Hardware wallets are the most secure wallet option because they keep your keys offline and in cold storage, this is why they are also called cold storage wallets. There are pros and cons to each. Hot wallets are generally more convenient, they tend to have a friendlier user interface and are easier to use. Cold wallets can be a bit of a hassle but are substantially more secure. TIP: To prevent hackers from making more money from their side-hustle it’s best practice to avoid using hot wallets for any bitcoin you plan on keeping long term. What are custodial and non-custodial wallets? Most people start off with their first buy and sell of bitcoin on an exchange, which holds your funds for you in a custodial wallet, where the exchange is taking custody of your private keys. When you move your funds off of an exchange into a wallet you control, you’re using a non-custodial wallet that allows you to store your own keys. Once I choose a wallet . . . How do I get a Bitcoin wallet and use it? Step 1: Choose which wallet app you’re going to use, then download the software. If you’re using a mobile device you can download a mobile app from the app store. Step 2: Open the software to create a wallet, private key, and mnemonic recovery phrase. Step 3: Write down your mnemonic and store it someplace safe. Step 4: Create a receive address and QR code. At this point you’re ready to receive bitcoin. Step 5: Share your wallet address or QR code to accept bitcoin. TIP: Make sure you’re set up with a Bitcoin BTC wallet and not one that is intended for Bitcoin Cash BCH. Bitcoin Cash is not Bitcoin, but Bitcoin Cash payments look a lot like bitcoin and it can potentially be a very expensive mistake to confuse the two. SECOND TIP: From a new user perspective, the experience of using bitcoin can feel like other online wallets or online payment methods. Yes, Bitcoin is an online payment system, but Bitcoin is also a digital currency. The properties of Bitcoin isn’t the same as loyalty cards, Apple pay, or even Samsung pay. Bitcoin may be the 2089 future of field communication NFC contactless payments, but bitcoin wallets have different properties from other mobile payment apps users are used to.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/22-choosing-a-bitcoin-wallet.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/22-choosing-a-bitcoin-wallet.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bitcoin Private Keys, Public Keys, and Addresses: The Basics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/16/what-is-a-bitcoin-private-key" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bitcoin Private Keys, Public Keys, and Addresses: The Basics" /><published>2020-05-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/16/what-is-a-bitcoin-private-key</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/16/what-is-a-bitcoin-private-key">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin uses cryptography to create a key pair that controls access to bitcoin on the blockchain. Each bitcoin key pair consists of a public and private key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-bitcoin-private-key&quot;&gt;What is a Bitcoin private key?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;bitcoin private key&lt;/strong&gt; is simply a large (256 bits) secret number that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;allows bitcoin to be unlocked and sent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Each private key creates a unique signature that authorizes the transaction of bitcoin for the owner. It’s called a private key because it is meant to be kept private and not shown to other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-bitcoin-public-key&quot;&gt;What is a Bitcoin public key?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;bitcoin public key&lt;/strong&gt; is another large number but &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;allows bitcoin to be locked and received&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s called a public key because it is meant to be shared publicly and enables you to receive funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-bitcoin-address&quot;&gt;What is a Bitcoin address?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bitcoin address is a hashed smaller version of the private key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-difference-between-private-and-public-keys&quot;&gt;What is the difference between private and public keys?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People can over-complicate explanations by trying to explain digital signatures, signing transactions, and wallet import formats. But the truth is most users don’t need any of this detail to understand the basics of how keys work in Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-can-think-of-public-key-cryptography-as-a-lock-but-with-two-keys-instead-of-one&quot;&gt;You can think of public-key cryptography as a lock, but with two keys instead of one:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/01-bitcoin-keys/bitcoin-privatekey-publickey-lock.png&quot; alt=&quot;bitcoin private key public key bitcoin clarity&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although you don’t need to understand cryptomagic to believe that it works, sometimes understanding the &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; is the key to being able to trust it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-the-bitcoin-private-key-relate-to-the-bitcoin-public-key&quot;&gt;How does the Bitcoin private key relate to the Bitcoin public key?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two keys (or numbers) are related mathematically on the secp256k1 elliptic curve. The private key is a randomly generated number plotted on the curve, and the corresponding public key is a related point on that curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real point of this magical curve is that it creates &lt;strong&gt;trap door functionality&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning that once we generate the first point on the curve (the private key) the corresponding second point (public key) is easily found but impossible to find in the opposite direction. If the user has the private key then the user always has the public key, but if other users have the public key it’s mathematically impossible for them to do the reverse to find the private key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-the-bitcoin-address-the-same-as-the-public-key&quot;&gt;Is the Bitcoin address the same as the public key?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;addresses-are-smaller-hashed-version-of-public-keys&quot;&gt;Addresses are smaller (hashed version) of public keys:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/01-bitcoin-keys/bitcoin-privatekey-publickey-address.png&quot; alt=&quot;bitcoin address public key bitcoin clarity&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;60%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because public kets come in different formats they can start with a 1 , 3 or bc1. There are uncompressed public keys, compressed public keys, and wif format. But what’s important to understand is that when you’re providing someone with a public address (or QR code) you’re giving them the ability to lock bitcoin on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-are-bitcoin-keys-and-addresses-generated&quot;&gt;How are bitcoin keys and addresses generated?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;
	&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed//QR1HZYod7Vs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bitcoin wallet software generates the users’ wallet file, addresses, and keys. The private is generated from a part of the software that is specially designed to be able to handle big numbers and generate them at random.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; To get a more hands-on understanding of this you can play around with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitaddress.org/bitaddress.org-v3.3.0-SHA256-dec17c07685e1870960903d8f58090475b25af946fe95a734f88408cef4aa194.html&quot;&gt;bitaddress.org&lt;/a&gt;, but don’t use for any real keys you plan on using, this is just a tool for understanding. For keys that you plan on using, you’ll want to use Bitcoin Core or a hardware wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-many-private-keys-are-there&quot;&gt;How many private keys are there?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There a lot, about 10 million million million million million million million million, or 115792089237316195423570985008687907852837564279074904382605163141518161494336 possible private keys to be exact. The number of possible keys is so large, that security of bitcoin relies on the assumption that no one will ever randomly generate the same two private keys twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-seed-phrase-or-mnemonic-recovery&quot;&gt;What is a seed phrase or mnemonic recovery?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A mnemonic phrase is a private key in a different form:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/01-bitcoin-keys/bitcoin-privatekey-generation-mnemonic-recovery.png&quot; alt=&quot;bitcoin mnemonic recovery phrase bitcoin clarity&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; width=&quot;90%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way numbers can be expressed as words (zero) and numerical digits (0), keys are just a really long string of numbers that have the same properties. Instead of using the word expression of the random number, the seed phrase uses a list of 12 or 24 random words to represent the random number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the mnemonic is to convert currency, money, and funds into human-readable words. So that the transfer of value can be written on to paper, or spoken over a cell phone and easily shared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; To add some security a password can also be added to the phrase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-best-way-to-store-bitcoin-private-keys-privately&quot;&gt;What is the best way to store Bitcoin private keys privately?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most secure way to store private keys safely is offline in cold storage, on a dedicated hardware device with your recovery mnemonic stored separately.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;picture&quot;=&gt;&quot;/img/about/kiara-bickers.jpg&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;kiarabickers&quot;}</name></author><summary type="html">Bitcoin uses cryptography to create a key pair that controls access to bitcoin on the blockchain. Each bitcoin key pair consists of a public and private key. What is a Bitcoin private key? A bitcoin private key is simply a large (256 bits) secret number that allows bitcoin to be unlocked and sent. Each private key creates a unique signature that authorizes the transaction of bitcoin for the owner. It’s called a private key because it is meant to be kept private and not shown to other people. What is a Bitcoin public key? A bitcoin public key is another large number but allows bitcoin to be locked and received. It’s called a public key because it is meant to be shared publicly and enables you to receive funds. What is a Bitcoin address? A bitcoin address is a hashed smaller version of the private key. What is the difference between private and public keys? People can over-complicate explanations by trying to explain digital signatures, signing transactions, and wallet import formats. But the truth is most users don’t need any of this detail to understand the basics of how keys work in Bitcoin. You can think of public-key cryptography as a lock, but with two keys instead of one: Although you don’t need to understand cryptomagic to believe that it works, sometimes understanding the how is the key to being able to trust it. How does the Bitcoin private key relate to the Bitcoin public key? These two keys (or numbers) are related mathematically on the secp256k1 elliptic curve. The private key is a randomly generated number plotted on the curve, and the corresponding public key is a related point on that curve. The real point of this magical curve is that it creates trap door functionality, meaning that once we generate the first point on the curve (the private key) the corresponding second point (public key) is easily found but impossible to find in the opposite direction. If the user has the private key then the user always has the public key, but if other users have the public key it’s mathematically impossible for them to do the reverse to find the private key. Is the Bitcoin address the same as the public key? Addresses are smaller (hashed version) of public keys: Because public kets come in different formats they can start with a 1 , 3 or bc1. There are uncompressed public keys, compressed public keys, and wif format. But what’s important to understand is that when you’re providing someone with a public address (or QR code) you’re giving them the ability to lock bitcoin on your behalf. How are bitcoin keys and addresses generated? The bitcoin wallet software generates the users’ wallet file, addresses, and keys. The private is generated from a part of the software that is specially designed to be able to handle big numbers and generate them at random. TIP: To get a more hands-on understanding of this you can play around with bitaddress.org, but don’t use for any real keys you plan on using, this is just a tool for understanding. For keys that you plan on using, you’ll want to use Bitcoin Core or a hardware wallet. How many private keys are there? There a lot, about 10 million million million million million million million million, or 115792089237316195423570985008687907852837564279074904382605163141518161494336 possible private keys to be exact. The number of possible keys is so large, that security of bitcoin relies on the assumption that no one will ever randomly generate the same two private keys twice. What is a seed phrase or mnemonic recovery? A mnemonic phrase is a private key in a different form: In the same way numbers can be expressed as words (zero) and numerical digits (0), keys are just a really long string of numbers that have the same properties. Instead of using the word expression of the random number, the seed phrase uses a list of 12 or 24 random words to represent the random number. The purpose of the mnemonic is to convert currency, money, and funds into human-readable words. So that the transfer of value can be written on to paper, or spoken over a cell phone and easily shared. TIP: To add some security a password can also be added to the phrase. What is the best way to store Bitcoin private keys privately? The most secure way to store private keys safely is offline in cold storage, on a dedicated hardware device with your recovery mnemonic stored separately.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/01-bitcoin-keys.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/01-bitcoin-keys.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>