<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-16T12:14:28-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/index.xml</id><title type="html">Kiara Bickers - Official Site | How to Get Started With Bitcoin</title><subtitle>Bitcoin Clarity explains what Bitcoin is, why it works, and if it can work for you.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bitcoin Private and Public Keys: The Basics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/bitcoin-public-private-keys" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bitcoin Private and Public Keys: The Basics" /><published>2020-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/bitcoin-public-private-keys</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/bitcoin-public-private-keys">&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin uses asymmetric or public-key cryptography to create a &lt;strong&gt;key pair&lt;/strong&gt; that controls your access to bitcoin on the blockchain. Each bitcoin key pair consists of a public and private key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-the-difference-between-the-bitcoin-private-key-vs-bitcoin-public-key&quot;&gt;What’s the difference between the bitcoin private key vs bitcoin public key?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;bitcoin private key&lt;/strong&gt; is simply a massive secret number that allows bitcoin to be unlocked, or decrypted, and sent. It’s called a &lt;em&gt;private&lt;/em&gt; key because it’s meant to stay concealed and hidden from other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;bitcoin public key&lt;/strong&gt; is another large number, but allows bitcoin to be locked and received. It’s called a &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; key because it’s meant to be shared with the person who is sending you bitcoin. The public key is generated from the private key but not vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-is-the-private-key-related-to-the-public-key&quot;&gt;How is the private key related to the public key?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Private and Public Keys are related mathematically on an a curve. Or, simply the two keys are just two numbers that are mathematically related on a elliptic curve, that’s why it’s called &lt;strong&gt;elliptic-curve cryptography&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Although you don’t need to understand this cryptomagic to believe that it works, sometimes understanding the &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; of technology is the key to being able to trust it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The math isn’t as simple, and neither is explaining it. But we can say that a bitcoin private key is randomly generated then plotted on the &lt;em&gt;secp256k1&lt;/em&gt; curve, and the bitcoin public key is the corresponding point on that curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still don’t get it? Still don’t understand how bitcoin keys relate . . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real point of this magical curve is that it creates &lt;em&gt;trap door&lt;/em&gt; functionality, meaning that once we have the first point on the curve (the private key) the corresponding second point (public key) is easily calculated but impossible to find in the opposite direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have the private key you always have the public key, but if you have the public key, itis impossible to find the private key. The trap door functionally makes this the perfect tool for the sending and receiving functionality that we have in the public-private keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-is-the-public-key-related-to-the-bitcoin-key-address&quot;&gt;How is the public key related to the bitcoin key address?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addresses are smaller versions of public keys that serve as your one-time location on the blockchain. When providing someone with a bitcoin address, you’re giving them the ability to lock, or encrypt bitcoin on your behalf, at a “location you control” with your private key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-are-bitcoin-private-keys-generated&quot;&gt;How are bitcoin private keys generated?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Random number generation is critical in nearly every cryptographic system, unfortunately, computers are fairly bad at generating random numbers. If the number was generated from computer code telling it how to be “random”, that would make it predictable.  Instead, the computer has to seed the random number function with data from outside of the code. To get feel for this you can play around with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitaddress.org/bitaddress.org-v3.3.0-SHA256-dec17c07685e1870960903d8f58090475b25af946fe95a734f88408cef4aa194.html&quot;&gt;bitaddress.org&lt;/a&gt; as an example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Core uses the OpenSSL library to seed the randomness needed to generate its random private keys. But not all wallets are using good sources of randomness, something you must  look out for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-many-bitcoin-private-keys-are-there&quot;&gt;How many bitcoin private keys are there?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot, 115792089237316195423570985008687907852837564279074904382605163141518161494336 to be exact. The number of possible keys is so large, that security of bitcoin relies on the assumption that no one will every randomly generate the same private key twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-mnemonic-phrase-mnemonic-recovery-phrase&quot;&gt;What is a mnemonic phrase, mnemonic recovery phrase?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way, numbers can be expressed as words (zero) and numerical digits (0), the private key is just a very large number that has the same properties. Instead of using the literal word expression of the random private key number (vigintillion, googol, or centillion), bitcoin uses a list of 12 or 24 random words to represent the random number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As specified in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0039.mediawiki&quot;&gt;BIP39&lt;/a&gt;, the motivation for this mnemonic is make private keys human-readable, so they can be easily written down as a backup to a private key, or spoken over the telephone and easily shared. A password can also be added to the phrase, to add some additional protection to your private key backup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-exactly-do-bitcoin-private-keys-work&quot;&gt;How exactly do bitcoin private keys work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Private keys work something like a cryptographic lock, that’s controlled by a smart contract called &lt;strong&gt;Bitcoin Script&lt;/strong&gt;. Scripts are stored in the inputs and outputs of a transaction and are the programs that control the locking/unlocking and sending/receiving funds on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is stored on the blockchain with a specific locking script that is only unlocked by it’s corresponding private key. When you want to spend or send that bitcoin by initiating a new transaction, the private key associated with that locking script now creates a signature to prove that it has the authority to move the coins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-are-the-bitcoins-actually-stored&quot;&gt;Where are the bitcoins actually stored?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blockchain is an evolution in databases, previously databases only recorded and logged transfers of value but on the blockchain, the value is stored on this ledger directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coins are stored in smart contracts (more specifically the scriptPubKey, also called the locking script or a UTXO) on the blockchain. When you initiate a transaction you create a signature with your private key, to unlock a specific batch of bitcoin on the blockchain, proving that you are authorized to move those funds. Your private key gives you control over your bitcoin and is not stored on the blockchain but in your wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-store-private-keys-safely&quot;&gt;How do you store private keys safely?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to keep your private keys safe is offline, in cold storage, on dedicated a hardware device, and with your mnemonic backup stored separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-i-want-to-store-my-own-private-keys&quot;&gt;Why should I want to store my own private keys?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storing and managing your private keys is the only way to have full control of your bitcoin. That being said, with great power comes great responsibility. If your private keys are misplaced, your backup is lost, if you trusted a wallet that you shouldn’t have, or you forgot to write down your backup entirely, there is no support number for you to call. Which is why it’s important to understand what you’re doing and educate yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;picture&quot;=&gt;&quot;/img/about/kiara-bickers.jpg&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;kiarabickers&quot;}</name></author><category term="bitcoin" /><category term="private" /><category term="keys," /><category term="bitcoin" /><category term="public" /><category term="keys" /><summary type="html">Bitcoin uses asymmetric or public-key cryptography to create a key pair that controls your access to bitcoin on the blockchain. Each bitcoin key pair consists of a public and private key. What’s the difference between the bitcoin private key vs bitcoin public key? A bitcoin private key is simply a massive secret number that allows bitcoin to be unlocked, or decrypted, and sent. It’s called a private key because it’s meant to stay concealed and hidden from other people. A bitcoin public key is another large number, but allows bitcoin to be locked and received. It’s called a public key because it’s meant to be shared with the person who is sending you bitcoin. The public key is generated from the private key but not vice versa. How is the private key related to the public key? Bitcoin Private and Public Keys are related mathematically on an a curve. Or, simply the two keys are just two numbers that are mathematically related on a elliptic curve, that’s why it’s called elliptic-curve cryptography. Although you don’t need to understand this cryptomagic to believe that it works, sometimes understanding the how of technology is the key to being able to trust it. The math isn’t as simple, and neither is explaining it. But we can say that a bitcoin private key is randomly generated then plotted on the secp256k1 curve, and the bitcoin public key is the corresponding point on that curve. Still don’t get it? Still don’t understand how bitcoin keys relate . . . The real point of this magical curve is that it creates trap door functionality, meaning that once we have the first point on the curve (the private key) the corresponding second point (public key) is easily calculated but impossible to find in the opposite direction. If you have the private key you always have the public key, but if you have the public key, itis impossible to find the private key. The trap door functionally makes this the perfect tool for the sending and receiving functionality that we have in the public-private keys. How is the public key related to the bitcoin key address? Addresses are smaller versions of public keys that serve as your one-time location on the blockchain. When providing someone with a bitcoin address, you’re giving them the ability to lock, or encrypt bitcoin on your behalf, at a “location you control” with your private key. How are bitcoin private keys generated? Random number generation is critical in nearly every cryptographic system, unfortunately, computers are fairly bad at generating random numbers. If the number was generated from computer code telling it how to be “random”, that would make it predictable. Instead, the computer has to seed the random number function with data from outside of the code. To get feel for this you can play around with bitaddress.org as an example. Bitcoin Core uses the OpenSSL library to seed the randomness needed to generate its random private keys. But not all wallets are using good sources of randomness, something you must look out for. How many bitcoin private keys are there? A lot, 115792089237316195423570985008687907852837564279074904382605163141518161494336 to be exact. The number of possible keys is so large, that security of bitcoin relies on the assumption that no one will every randomly generate the same private key twice. What is a mnemonic phrase, mnemonic recovery phrase? In the same way, numbers can be expressed as words (zero) and numerical digits (0), the private key is just a very large number that has the same properties. Instead of using the literal word expression of the random private key number (vigintillion, googol, or centillion), bitcoin uses a list of 12 or 24 random words to represent the random number. As specified in BIP39, the motivation for this mnemonic is make private keys human-readable, so they can be easily written down as a backup to a private key, or spoken over the telephone and easily shared. A password can also be added to the phrase, to add some additional protection to your private key backup. How exactly do bitcoin private keys work? Private keys work something like a cryptographic lock, that’s controlled by a smart contract called Bitcoin Script. Scripts are stored in the inputs and outputs of a transaction and are the programs that control the locking/unlocking and sending/receiving funds on the blockchain. Bitcoin is stored on the blockchain with a specific locking script that is only unlocked by it’s corresponding private key. When you want to spend or send that bitcoin by initiating a new transaction, the private key associated with that locking script now creates a signature to prove that it has the authority to move the coins. Where are the bitcoins actually stored? The blockchain is an evolution in databases, previously databases only recorded and logged transfers of value but on the blockchain, the value is stored on this ledger directly. Coins are stored in smart contracts (more specifically the scriptPubKey, also called the locking script or a UTXO) on the blockchain. When you initiate a transaction you create a signature with your private key, to unlock a specific batch of bitcoin on the blockchain, proving that you are authorized to move those funds. Your private key gives you control over your bitcoin and is not stored on the blockchain but in your wallet. How do you store private keys safely? The best way to keep your private keys safe is offline, in cold storage, on dedicated a hardware device, and with your mnemonic backup stored separately. Why should I want to store my own private keys? Storing and managing your private keys is the only way to have full control of your bitcoin. That being said, with great power comes great responsibility. If your private keys are misplaced, your backup is lost, if you trusted a wallet that you shouldn’t have, or you forgot to write down your backup entirely, there is no support number for you to call. Which is why it’s important to understand what you’re doing and educate yourself.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/01-bitcoin-keys.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bitcoin Basics: The Best Bitcoin Wallet For You</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/black-box-thinking" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bitcoin Basics: The Best Bitcoin Wallet For You" /><published>2020-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/black-box-thinking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/black-box-thinking">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-best-bitcoin-wallet&quot;&gt;What is the best bitcoin wallet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-help-you-choose-a-bitcoin-wallet---&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let’s help you choose a bitcoin wallet . . .&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-decide-if-you-want-to-store-your-own-keys&quot;&gt;Step 1: Decide if you want to store your own keys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Controlling your own private keys are the only way to be fully in control and have access to your bitcoin, but that also means that you’re fully responsibly for protecting your keys and its backup. Exchanges or custodial wallets will provide the service of storing your private keys on your behalf, which is great for new users. But this also means that you’re full relying on the exchange to be a custodian of your private keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; For long-term storage consider using a hardware wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2-do-you-prioritize-privacy-or-security&quot;&gt;Step 2: Do you prioritize privacy or security?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Bitcoin, there are privacy focused wallets and there are security focused wallets. The goal of privacy focused wallets is to stop your transactions on the blockchain from being linked back to use. They do this using the CoinJoin protocol, the Tor anonymity network, and allow for manual coin labeling and selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security focused wallets are hardware wallets, cold storage, that allow you to store your bitcoin offline making them less vulnerable a range of different hacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; For privacy AND security, you can use a privacy wallet with a hardware wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SECOND TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; Be extra cautious when using a mobile wallet. Consider only using mobile wallets for small values of bitcoin, since they are not great at privacy or security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-decide-if-you-want-to-validate-your-own-transactions&quot;&gt;Step 3: Decide if you want to validate your own transactions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running MyNode&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to validate your own transactions is the only way to get the fully properties of the Bitcoin system. You can validate the entire history of the blockchain with a full node or just your own transactions with a light node/SPV Wallet. In either case, running something like MyNode is one of the simplest ways to get started with validating your bitcoin transactions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;picture&quot;=&gt;&quot;/img/about/kiara-bickers.jpg&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;kiarabickers&quot;}</name></author><category term="bitcoin" /><category term="wallets" /><summary type="html">What is the best bitcoin wallet? Let’s help you choose a bitcoin wallet . . . Step 1: Decide if you want to store your own keys Controlling your own private keys are the only way to be fully in control and have access to your bitcoin, but that also means that you’re fully responsibly for protecting your keys and its backup. Exchanges or custodial wallets will provide the service of storing your private keys on your behalf, which is great for new users. But this also means that you’re full relying on the exchange to be a custodian of your private keys. TIP: For long-term storage consider using a hardware wallet. Step 2: Do you prioritize privacy or security? In Bitcoin, there are privacy focused wallets and there are security focused wallets. The goal of privacy focused wallets is to stop your transactions on the blockchain from being linked back to use. They do this using the CoinJoin protocol, the Tor anonymity network, and allow for manual coin labeling and selection. Security focused wallets are hardware wallets, cold storage, that allow you to store your bitcoin offline making them less vulnerable a range of different hacks. TIP: For privacy AND security, you can use a privacy wallet with a hardware wallet. SECOND TIP: Be extra cautious when using a mobile wallet. Consider only using mobile wallets for small values of bitcoin, since they are not great at privacy or security. Step 3: Decide if you want to validate your own transactions Running MyNode Being able to validate your own transactions is the only way to get the fully properties of the Bitcoin system. You can validate the entire history of the blockchain with a full node or just your own transactions with a light node/SPV Wallet. In either case, running something like MyNode is one of the simplest ways to get started with validating your bitcoin transactions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/02-bitcoin-wallets.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bitcoin Basics: The Best Bitcoin Wallet For You</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/how-bitcoin-wallets-work" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bitcoin Basics: The Best Bitcoin Wallet For You" /><published>2020-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/how-bitcoin-wallets-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/how-bitcoin-wallets-work">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-best-bitcoin-wallet&quot;&gt;What is the best bitcoin wallet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-help-you-choose-a-bitcoin-wallet---&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let’s help you choose a bitcoin wallet . . .&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-decide-if-you-want-to-store-your-own-keys&quot;&gt;Step 1: Decide if you want to store your own keys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Controlling your own private keys are the only way to be fully in control and have access to your bitcoin, but that also means that you’re fully responsibly for protecting your keys and its backup. Exchanges or custodial wallets will provide the service of storing your private keys on your behalf, which is great for new users. But this also means that you’re full relying on the exchange to be a custodian of your private keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; For long-term storage consider using a hardware wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2-do-you-prioritize-privacy-or-security&quot;&gt;Step 2: Do you prioritize privacy or security?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Bitcoin, there are privacy focused wallets and there are security focused wallets. The goal of privacy focused wallets is to stop your transactions on the blockchain from being linked back to use. They do this using the CoinJoin protocol, the Tor anonymity network, and allow for manual coin labeling and selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security focused wallets are hardware wallets, cold storage, that allow you to store your bitcoin offline making them less vulnerable a range of different hacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; For privacy AND security, you can use a privacy wallet with a hardware wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SECOND TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; Be extra cautious when using a mobile wallet. Consider only using mobile wallets for small values of bitcoin, since they are not great at privacy or security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-decide-if-you-want-to-validate-your-own-transactions&quot;&gt;Step 3: Decide if you want to validate your own transactions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running MyNode&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to validate your own transactions is the only way to get the fully properties of the Bitcoin system. You can validate the entire history of the blockchain with a full node or just your own transactions with a light node/SPV Wallet. In either case, running something like MyNode is one of the simplest ways to get started with validating your bitcoin transactions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;picture&quot;=&gt;&quot;/img/about/kiara-bickers.jpg&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;kiarabickers&quot;}</name></author><category term="bitcoin" /><category term="wallets" /><summary type="html">What is the best bitcoin wallet? Let’s help you choose a bitcoin wallet . . . Step 1: Decide if you want to store your own keys Controlling your own private keys are the only way to be fully in control and have access to your bitcoin, but that also means that you’re fully responsibly for protecting your keys and its backup. Exchanges or custodial wallets will provide the service of storing your private keys on your behalf, which is great for new users. But this also means that you’re full relying on the exchange to be a custodian of your private keys. TIP: For long-term storage consider using a hardware wallet. Step 2: Do you prioritize privacy or security? In Bitcoin, there are privacy focused wallets and there are security focused wallets. The goal of privacy focused wallets is to stop your transactions on the blockchain from being linked back to use. They do this using the CoinJoin protocol, the Tor anonymity network, and allow for manual coin labeling and selection. Security focused wallets are hardware wallets, cold storage, that allow you to store your bitcoin offline making them less vulnerable a range of different hacks. TIP: For privacy AND security, you can use a privacy wallet with a hardware wallet. SECOND TIP: Be extra cautious when using a mobile wallet. Consider only using mobile wallets for small values of bitcoin, since they are not great at privacy or security. Step 3: Decide if you want to validate your own transactions Running MyNode Being able to validate your own transactions is the only way to get the fully properties of the Bitcoin system. You can validate the entire history of the blockchain with a full node or just your own transactions with a light node/SPV Wallet. In either case, running something like MyNode is one of the simplest ways to get started with validating your bitcoin transactions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/02-bitcoin-wallets.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Blockchain as A Timechain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/timechain-not-blockchain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Blockchain as A Timechain" /><published>2020-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/timechain-not-blockchain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/timechain-not-blockchain">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ymAYDdffKXM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wwu7JED2tnM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;picture&quot;=&gt;&quot;/img/about/kiara-bickers.jpg&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;kiarabickers&quot;}</name></author><category term="bitcoin" /><category term="wallets" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/04-timechain-not-blockchain.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bitcoin Basics: The Best Bitcoin Wallet For You</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/bitcoin-or-altcoins" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bitcoin Basics: The Best Bitcoin Wallet For You" /><published>2020-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/bitcoin-or-altcoins</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/bitcoin-or-altcoins">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-best-bitcoin-wallet&quot;&gt;What is the best bitcoin wallet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-help-you-choose-a-bitcoin-wallet---&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let’s help you choose a bitcoin wallet . . .&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-1-decide-if-you-want-to-store-your-own-keys&quot;&gt;Step 1: Decide if you want to store your own keys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Controlling your own private keys are the only way to be fully in control and have access to your bitcoin, but that also means that you’re fully responsibly for protecting your keys and its backup. Exchanges or custodial wallets will provide the service of storing your private keys on your behalf, which is great for new users. But this also means that you’re full relying on the exchange to be a custodian of your private keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; For long-term storage consider using a hardware wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-2-do-you-prioritize-privacy-or-security&quot;&gt;Step 2: Do you prioritize privacy or security?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Bitcoin, there are privacy focused wallets and there are security focused wallets. The goal of privacy focused wallets is to stop your transactions on the blockchain from being linked back to use. They do this using the CoinJoin protocol, the Tor anonymity network, and allow for manual coin labeling and selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security focused wallets are hardware wallets, cold storage, that allow you to store your bitcoin offline making them less vulnerable a range of different hacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; For privacy AND security, you can use a privacy wallet with a hardware wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SECOND TIP:&lt;/strong&gt; Be extra cautious when using a mobile wallet. Consider only using mobile wallets for small values of bitcoin, since they are not great at privacy or security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-3-decide-if-you-want-to-validate-your-own-transactions&quot;&gt;Step 3: Decide if you want to validate your own transactions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running MyNode&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to validate your own transactions is the only way to get the fully properties of the Bitcoin system. You can validate the entire history of the blockchain with a full node or just your own transactions with a light node/SPV Wallet. In either case, running something like MyNode is one of the simplest ways to get started with validating your bitcoin transactions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;picture&quot;=&gt;&quot;/img/about/kiara-bickers.jpg&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;kiarabickers&quot;}</name></author><category term="bitcoin" /><category term="wallets" /><summary type="html">What is the best bitcoin wallet? Let’s help you choose a bitcoin wallet . . . Step 1: Decide if you want to store your own keys Controlling your own private keys are the only way to be fully in control and have access to your bitcoin, but that also means that you’re fully responsibly for protecting your keys and its backup. Exchanges or custodial wallets will provide the service of storing your private keys on your behalf, which is great for new users. But this also means that you’re full relying on the exchange to be a custodian of your private keys. TIP: For long-term storage consider using a hardware wallet. Step 2: Do you prioritize privacy or security? In Bitcoin, there are privacy focused wallets and there are security focused wallets. The goal of privacy focused wallets is to stop your transactions on the blockchain from being linked back to use. They do this using the CoinJoin protocol, the Tor anonymity network, and allow for manual coin labeling and selection. Security focused wallets are hardware wallets, cold storage, that allow you to store your bitcoin offline making them less vulnerable a range of different hacks. TIP: For privacy AND security, you can use a privacy wallet with a hardware wallet. SECOND TIP: Be extra cautious when using a mobile wallet. Consider only using mobile wallets for small values of bitcoin, since they are not great at privacy or security. Step 3: Decide if you want to validate your own transactions Running MyNode Being able to validate your own transactions is the only way to get the fully properties of the Bitcoin system. You can validate the entire history of the blockchain with a full node or just your own transactions with a light node/SPV Wallet. In either case, running something like MyNode is one of the simplest ways to get started with validating your bitcoin transactions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/blog/thumbnails/02-bitcoin-wallets.jpg" /></entry></feed>